summarize my day, summarize my week,
what are my calendar events, like that
phrase. Exactly. And that is a better PC
if you can pone that versus the user
saying hello, hi, whatever. You know
what I mean?
>> Such a that is such a good call out,
Rezo. That is a really good call out.
>> Best part of Viking when you can just,
you know, critical think right.
[music]
>> [laughter]
[gasps]
>> Yeah, dude.
>> All right, hackers. Look, we got a lot I
don't I don't know if you guys know
this, but there's a lot more to CTV than
just the podcast. Okay, I'm just going
to list a couple things you guys might
be interested in real quick. Okay, we
got the Discord. That's where a lot of
awesome conversations are happening.
This cool research channel in particular
is amazing on the Discord. We've got the
full-time hunters guild for those of you
making over 100K a year in Bug Bounty.
If you're looking to be around other
elite hackers, that's the place to do
it. We've got the critical thinkers tier
on the Discord. That's where we uh
that's like our inner circle. That's
where we share all of our scripts, do
exclusive AMAs, master classes, that
sort of thing. And we've got the
research lab over at lab.ctb.show
where if you've got a piece of research
you'd like to submit, you can submit it
there and we may take it hosted on the
blog and cover it on the pod for you.
Um, also underappreciated, but we also
have the swag store, guys. So, hit the
swag link over at ctbb.show
and you guys can buy some cool t-shirts
uh with critical thinking um you know,
slogan and stuff like that on it. All
right. Um, with that, let's go back to
the show. Check out some of those
things. All right, we're going to go
back to the show, but check out those
things for me. All right, let's go.
All right, sub hackers. Welcome to the
this weekend bug bounty segment. We got
a couple news items that did not make it
into the episode that I wanted to make
sure got in front of you guys. The first
one warms the heart. It is our boy
Ronnie Carter um loopin was featured in
a hacker one blog by Maggie Miller. Um
so definitely go check this out if you
want to hear more about Ronnie's story.
If you guys are been listening to the
pod, you probably know a good amount
about Ronnie's story. But Deppy, his um
supply chain product is amazing. One of
the best uh supply chain products out
there. Really doing a lot of uh unique
research in that arena as well. Um so if
you want to learn more, you can check
out the link. We'll we'll put it in the
description. It's on the hacker 1 blog
under Ronnie Carta bug bounty. Next is
uh Kaido actually released a new plugin
called off swap. This is by Bevix. Um
and this one I just wanted to show you
guys this for those of you that are um
watching on YouTube. It's just a really
awesome plugin that allows you to swap
your session super easy. So you define
these user profiles. You say okay set
this cookie for this user, set this
cookie for that user, right? And then um
it just puts these buttons in your
replay where you've got user A, user B
and you can just press them and it
applies that transformation to your open
replay requests, right? So it makes it
really easy for you to swap sessions and
go after those O vulnerabilities which
are just everywhere. Um we're releasing
a lot of stuff like this with Kaido
right now. We've got like I know some
some people have been doing Oify,
there's authorize, there's Omatrix,
there's O swap. So um there's a lot of
O- based plugin for whatever you are
going after in Kaido and we've also got
some shift stuff coming there too. So be
on the lookout there but this is a very
manual approach right and I know that
aligns with some of the bug bounty
hunters that really like to do
everything themselves to ensure full
coverage. So check out odd swap if
you're interested in that. Okay last is
something a little interesting I wanted
to tell you guys about Takumi. Okay,
Takumi is uh GMO securities uh flat
securities um continuous source code re
review AI. Okay, so there are a lot of
people building AI products right now,
but I know I know the guys that are
building this and I know that Takumi is
amazing. Okay, the way that it's
implemented, it does an excellent job
and it's very affordable. If you go to
the website flat.te/takumi,
t a ku mi, um then you can check it out.
It's very affordable. It's free for open
source products, right? Zero yen per
month. And uh the basic plan is seven
mon, which is 70,000
uh yen, which is about $450 USD. Um and
this contains I think what it says here
is that it contains about one month's
worth of credits where you can do source
code review. Okay. Um using the AI. Very
good stuff. very good results out of
here from what I've seen under the hood.
Wanted to make you guys aware of that.
This is like really the S tier stuff in
Japan. So, if you're wanting to try to
understand, you know, take advantage of
what um what companies are ahead in
other markets, then you should
definitely check out Takumi because they
are ahead in my opinion. Um all right,
that's all I had for this week. Let's
get back to the show.
All right, man. I feel like I got to be
real with the audience on this one. Like
[laughter and gasps] right before I'm
like squeezing this little stress ball
thing so hard right now cuz right before
we got on the air I have been fighting
with a CSS issue and this plugin that
I'm coding for like an hour an hour and
a half and I just
>> it's totally not even worth your time.
But
>> I'm about to lose it, dude. CSS I I
freaking love CSS, but I hate CSS, dude.
I really do.
>> Um
>> why is it so complicated? It feels like
it's like um a stack of
>> [snorts]
>> layered complexity on top of a million
other things. And I know you
specifically are complaining about
Tailwinds as like another uh
>> you know, I love I love the Kaida team.
I love them. I love them to death, but
they they're on this whole Tailwind kick
and I just can't get behind it. And I
just don't like the added complexity of
like classes and oh, did it did it like
generate the correct class? I don't
know. There's just there's all sorts of
stuff with it, but Has Has Yon given you
his bullcase for it? Like about it.
>> He has he has and he's right, of course,
you know, but but for me like I I
you know, I'm just a simple hacker, you
know, man. I'm not a dev, you know. I I
just all I want to do is just like pop
open dev panels, tweak it to how I want
it to look, copy the CSS, put it in
there, you know, like put it in inline
SC, you know, like [laughter] whatever.
>> But um
>> yeah. Okay. All right.
>> Just breathing just breathing through
this. Uh,
>> so what you're what you're actually
saying for the listener is if they hear
any rage behind your voice about
anything, it's not intended at the
content. It's just you've got this like
>> it's Ian's fault is what it is.
>> Yeah, it's Ian's fault.
>> Yeah. No. Um, [laughter]
uh, all right, dude. Let's get to it.
Um,
well, actually, okay, before we jump
into the Defcon Fun, uh, I do want to
talk to the listeners about a new, um,
research piece that popped up through
the lab. So, let me go ahead and get
that up. I thought I had it up before
but I don't. Um but this is just a cool
once again we are trying to incentivize
people with uh the research lab to do
little micro blogs with cool you know
two paragraph you know this one's a
little longer but the tlddr is pretty
short like hey this is what I found this
is how it worked maybe you can use this
little gadget right I just think that's
so valuable
>> um
>> super valuable
>> yeah and so um this one was awesome uh
this one was actually relating to
unicode surrogates uh and how I didn't
really think about how they would affect
um the specific databases uh and the
them being converted via unic code
normalization or not knowing how to
represent these things into the question
mark character, right? Um,
>> so here's the here's the write up right
here. And the TLDDR of it is, you know,
there are some scenarios in which these
Unicode surrogates in particular, you
know, other unic codes may not, but
these surrogates that are often used in
emojis, um, will get normalized into a
question mark character. And the
question mark character obviously we
know, you know, I I thought about in the
context of URLs, okay, you know, it's
going to truncate the URL, whatever.
That's really
>> basically like two separate conversions.
like one thing is falling back into a
question mark like character and then
it's being translated to the question
mark later.
>> Uh I'm I'm not sure that could that's a
great point. It could be like um that
conversion between unic code into the
unic code question mark and then the
unic code question mark into the into
the actual normal question mark.
>> That's that's how I understood. Yeah.
>> Yeah. It it certainly could be. But
however it worked out, it it panned out.
um this character uh and uh other unic
code characters, this specifically one
is um unic code point DC2A was being
converted into a question mark and that
question mark was then being converted
into a wildcard character in solar or
elastic search. He's not sure which one
uh because of the of the situation, but
he he looked into it and found two
databases that use it as a wild card
character.
>> Um so that is clutch. Uh, and I I
totally didn't think about it in like
the the SQL or like the database
perspective, right? Um, versus like the
URL uh query parameter perspective.
>> Yeah. So, is this basically like when
you're fuzzing like when you're looking
for interesting things and you're
looking for characters that might bypass
specific um like parsing or things like
that? Uh, people just need to be aware
of potentially testing for surrogate
pairs.
>> Yeah, exactly. and and seeing if those
are normalizing into question marks and
whether those question marks the big
thing for me is that oh of course those
question marks can can be converted into
you know wild card characters. That was
that was the big thing because I knew
you know I know unic code normalization
sometimes through the pipes or whatever
ends up with a with a question mark at
some point. Um right but specifically
this surrogate uh is does this and then
results in a question mark which can be
uh used as a wild card in a database
wasn't something I'd really really
thought through.
>> Yeah, I feel like it always get
normalized to the question mark inside
the little square icon. So I bet then
that's getting converted to a real
question mark which is being interpreted
as the wild card.
>> And if it even if it wasn't in his
scenario, I'm sure that does exist. That
scenario does exist. So
>> yeah.
>> Um all right, dude. So, for this
episode, we kind of went back through a
bunch of different Defcon videos that
that finally got posted and we finally
got around to actually uh watching them
and tried to pull out some juicy
goodness for you guys listener. Um I've
got, let's see, one, two, three, four,
five. Five talks that I can talk about.
Uh I don't know how many you grabbed,
but um
>> I've got one, two, three, four, five.
But mine's more like three and then like
two that are so deeply technical on
things that I'm not an expert in. But I
still pulled out some like things that I
thought were worth mentioning.
>> Yeah, dude. And then you've got like
some mega list over here as well.
>> Oh, I I just put the whole list of the
Bug Bounty Village talks in case we
wanted to like uh comment on those. I
mean, obviously so many people that we
know well and so I didn't know if there
were any of these that you had heard
good things about or had heard
mentioned. So, I just put the full list
in here. Dude, I was I was a little
salty to not be able to make it to a lot
of the talks this year. Like I I had to
like in and out Defcon this year.
>> Um and
>> do you know if those were recorded or if
they'll be put up anywhere?
>> I feel like I heard they're not or
something.
>> Sort of recorded I think. Uh so I'm I I
messaged Harley and I'm trying to get
like you know I'm trying to see if he'll
just give me the recordings so that I
can you know can some of the information
down. But um yeah I think they'll be up
eventually I think.
>> Okay. Yeah. complete.
>> Um, but let's dive into it. Um, the
first one that I Okay. Well, first, we
can't talk about Defcon talks without
mentioning the HTTP 1.1 must die uh from
James Kettle and the Portswiger research
team. We're not going to talk about that
because we did a whole episode on that
already. So, go listen to that episode
if you um if you haven't already. Uh the
one that I wanted to start off with is
actually Prompt Scan Exploit AI's
journey through zero days uh by the Expo
team. And this one was interesting
because they didn't actually get to give
the talk at Defcon. They had to uh
record it afterwards and post it on the
website. Um so this video I think only
has like a thousand something views.
Very few people
>> really bleeding. I haven't seen it. I
need to go watch it.
>> It's it's it's good, man. There's a lot
of good content in there. So um let me
let me pick out a couple of the things.
You should definitely go watch it
yourself, but um let me pick out a
couple of the the key points for me. Um
so the first one is they kind of you
know about halfway through the talk you
know they cover all like the um how expo
works and like uh the output things that
they do the blog posts off of. Um they
covered those but then later on they
covered the challenges that they faced
while building Expo that bug bounty
hunters should be aware of if they're
building their own AI systems which I
happen to be doing right now. [laughter]
uh you know so I was like oh this is
very interesting but the first challenge
that they came up against was saying
that they noted was AI costs uh are are
high versus traditional costs but they
they really did map this out and we've
seen this time and time again uh AI
costs are going to continue to drop we
saw a 76% cut um uh what is this between
uh Gemini Pro 1.5 at launch and uh
Gemini 1.5 Pro in 2024 um and have to of
2024. So, and we're going to see and we
saw another 86% drop um after that. So,
like the costs are just continuing to
just tank for these things.
>> Um and so,
>> and even if like let's say I do think a
lot of people um might be skeptical
about that.
>> There are many people I know which I
don't necessarily agree with that think
that the bubble's going to pop and that
this is basically companies burn burning
>> investor funds, right? Like, yeah,
they're just trying to mass adopt users.
But I think that what's really crazy and
really cool is that so many of these
models are like they get distilled, they
get reused, they get fine-tuned, they
like it seems like even when the like
let's say even if the latest and
greatest models went up in price, which
I don't actually know that I believe
they will, the previous models which are
just still insanely good like Gemini 2.0
Flash and like even even this it's like
uh in the screenshot it's 1.5, right?
They're already at 2.5 and I think three
just recently came out or is at least in
testing already on like some of the
battle arena sites. And so I think like
um even if price the prices don't like
stay low forever, these older models are
still really capable for things like
this.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So essentially their
takeaway here was like don't worry about
cost of AI right now. Exactly.
>> You know, just build it and then
eventually, you know, the the older
models are going to be so cheap it's
like who gives a lily, you know.
>> Um and I I do agree with that. And I
also think uh models that are open
source are also getting pretty good. Um,
and so then you kind of just have to pay
for energy,
>> which is not which which by the way is
not uh inconsequential, you know, like
like it does cost money, real money,
guys. Uh, your energy bill will feel it
if you're running like AI stuff
constantly. Um, I once was like
calculating out, oh, you know, I got
this big server from the store or, you
know, and I was like, oh, I'm going to
run it in my basement and kill my VPS
costs. And I'm like calculating out. I'm
like, "Oh [__] this is going to cost me
like $15 a month in electricity. I
should just spin up a VPS, you know?"
>> Exactly. [laughter] Yep. Exactly.
>> So, yeah, there are some gotchas there.
Um, okay, challenge three,
>> skipping over a couple.
>> Too many assets, right?
>> They were saying, "Okay, this is um a
problem. We've got too many URLs, too
many things to scan." So, they did a
couple things. One, they they used uh
they parsed the scope. Easy peasy. We're
not going to talk about that. I'm going
to talk about the two other things.
Scoring and dduplication. Okay, scoring
and dduplication. Scoring is uh
essentially the way they approached
identifying which targets are
interesting. They created like this
massive 80, it looked like 80 or so
attribute list for these targets. It
says, does it have GraphQL? Does it have
forms? Does it have an API? Does it have
a password reset? You know th those sort
of things, yes or no. And then it asked
the AI those questions and and rated
each one of the the hosts, right? And
then it would focus on the host that has
the highest scoring rating. Um
>> like it's almost like a likelihood to be
vulnerable type scoring. Like if it's a
like if it's a plain hello world page
with nothing on it, it would just rank
at a zero because there's no
functionality there, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. And and um and so
and you know, obviously there are
situations where oh it's like you know
there's some hidden path or whatever.
Um, but I mean this is this is a good
start and I think that cut down about
45% of their targets. You know, they
they're able to focus more on the top,
you know, 45%.
>> Well, the reason why I love this, I've
obviously talked to a lot of Hackbot
companies. the vast majority are not
approaching Hackbot in this way. Like um
the thing that I love that Expo has done
all the way since the beginning relative
to other Hackbot companies is like it's
felt like they wanted to be a full
blackbox like here you're given this bug
bounty program now go like attack it.
>> Yeah.
>> Um I the majority of other companies
they just take input as URL.
>> And so like they're not even worried
about the problem of like which domain
do I look at? So I I think it's just
kind of cool that they even um wanted to
solve this problem in the first place.
Like that it was a part of their desire
was to actually decide which subdomains
to look at.
>> It's a part of the bug bounty design,
man. You know, it it really is. You
know, these guys are bringing a bunch of
bug bounty automation experience into
this whole thing. Uh which is invaluable
to expo, I'm sure.
>> Um so the next one was dduplication. I
think this one was interesting because
we've I I've seen a bunch of people try
to address this problem, right? We've
seen the top hackers, you know, in the
automation world try to address this.
Sometimes you do visual distance based
off of screenshots. Sometimes you do
like DOM hashing. You par you, you you
know parse the DOM and you try to like
use SIM hash and like uh you know
>> strip out the dynamic content rather
than hash it.
>> Yeah. And you try to figure out what's
dynamic and what's not. Um the one that
they mentioned here that was very
interesting was they use text content uh
and embeddings.
>> Yeah.
>> And then
Exactly. So I'm like okay you know this
is a very interesting thing here like um
we're not necessarily uh you know going
to be using AI here but we are doing
this embedding process right you know or
like we're not going to be using LLM's
like hey you know take this and like
tell me what it is you know um but
instead you are using some of the core
technology behind it that allows you to
take meaning and assign it to like a a
vector you know a a um a series of
numbers
>> and then um you know use that to
identify Okay, you know, are these, you
know, what is the cosign difference
between this one and this one and say,
okay, wow, these are really similar,
like we should, these are probably
dupes, right? So, so then you ddup uh
much more efficiently there based off of
meaning, you know, versus off of like
whatever visual display or or um uh you
know, whatever hashing that techniques
we have. So, I just thought that was a
really unique um way of solving that
problem. It's super cool and my thing
like immediately my brain jumps to I
want to see it in visual space. I want
to see a threedimensional like node
graph of oh which I mean I guess they
actually do have that for image based
already, don't they? But anyways, yeah,
for vectorbased I feel like it's like
actually representation of really what
you're what the vectors are. You know,
of course you're condensing down some
sort of like 1 million dimension space
down to like 3D, but it would be cool to
see like little clusters of domains
based on that.
>> Dude, that would be sick. [laughter]
That would be totally sick. I totally
that was not where my brain went at all.
My brain was like my brain was like
great
>> dduplication.
>> Well, yeah. Well, anytime I think of
vector space that's how I visualize it.
It's just like a big 3D space and you
know by vectorzing you're taking that
content and you're putting it at a
single point. And so whenever you say
cosine similarity distance I think oh
those points are really close in that 3D
space. And so now what what do I want to
see for um uniqueness for like uh
anomalies is like what's not close to
the other ones. So I imagine if you
mapped it on to 3D space, you would see
a whole bunch of domains that are all
together and then you would see some
like that are like kind of off on their
own and it'd be cool to be able to just
click those to go to them.
>> Yeah, that would be cool. That'd be
super cool.
>> Yeah. Um so yeah, I thought that was
really unique. Um the the next challenge
that they they represented was
boundaries, you know, setting setting
scope, staying in scope, that sort of
thing. And they one of the ways that
they did this was they um implemented
dynamic DNS uh for this whole thing. So
they're just not resolving some of the
domains that are not in in their scope.
And I think that that is a good solution
to solve it at the DNS level. Um, you
know, some of the LLM stuff can
>> it's gonna break so many sides though.
>> Yeah. Yeah, it could. But, uh, I think
you can also do some contextual
awareness on it, right? Like, uh, let's
say it's loading a third party script or
whatever. Um, and that third party
script, you know, you need to respond
with like, you know, you sandbag it to
your server and respond it with like a
200 and an empty js file or something
like that, you know. Um, I
>> I feel like it's better just to like not
let it modify requests to sites that
aren't in scope. just still let it load
>> or maybe like let it load stuff but like
don't let it target it
>> focus don't let it send request to that
yeah
>> yeah I thought that was interesting and
then um oh uh so challenge number seven
number eight was essentially this whole
concept of how do we get the most out of
the models and what they were saying is
they actually saw a really big increase
in efficacy when switching back and
forth between different models
essentially like every rotation of the
agent flip a coin, pick a model, you
know, like and and just, you know,
distribute it, right? You going for like
the stat statistical approach because
what'll happen is one model will get
stuck,
>> right? And it'll get stuck and it'll
rotate, it'll rotate, it'll rotate, but
you know, somewhere in that rotation, a
different model's getting added in to
the mix and then that model will bring
its own perspective and then that'll get
handed back to the other model and
that's the breakthrough needed to like
continue going further, right? So just
like by subbing in and out different
models, you get differences in approach
and um and they said that that increased
efficacy a lot, which I was kind of
surprised because I feel like it'd be
kind of a scatteredrained like, oh, let
me try this. Oh, let me try this. No,
I'm going to go this way. But really, it
seemed to to work well from what they
said.
>> Yeah, I remember I think we covered that
on like a podcast episode a little bit
ago when they kind of first published
that paper or maybe when we were talking
to Diego, we mentioned that. But yeah, I
agree. I I think that models today all
feel so similar. they all are like as
long as you're getting ones in the same
class, right? Like if you're comparing
GPT5 to Gemini 25 Pro to Claude 4 or
whatever, it feels like they're all like
kind of the same intelligence. Uh but
yeah, I mean I guess that the internal
structures are like very different and
so you're going to get like different
approaches, different attempts.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And then the last thing that
they mentioned was there are diminishing
returns on number of rotations per
vulnerability type. Um so you know what
they're saying is okay
you know it typically only on average
it's only going to take me you know
eight times or whatever to get this
excss
>> uh and then it it produces diminishing
returns right so like for per
vulnerability class understand where the
optimal point of ROI is on number of
rotations uh versus output of valid
vulnerabilities and then limit your
agent to that to maximize like your your
output of vulnerabil abilities because
instead you can allocate those computing
resources to another endpoint which is
going to produce more vulnerabilities.
Um
>> yeah, it's so cool that you can
basically gify anything these days. Like
you can create an evaluation and so I'm
sure that's what they did, right? They
were like, "Oh, let's create an
evaluation and figure out if it hasn't
figured out by four steps, it's never
going to figure it out. So just don't
waste any cycles after that and just
stop right at four steps, you know?"
>> Yeah. Yeah. Pretty solid. So overall, a
really good talk. Definitely underrated.
Uh I'm going to link it in the
description. You guys should check it
out. Um, anybody who's even remotely
thinking about using AI or integrating
AI, uh, or creating an AI hacking
product should check that out because
there's a lot of lessons learned and
they're sharing very freely. Um, so all
right. Um, you want to take the next
one?
>> Yes. And you had a different opinion on
this one, so I think it's going to be
kind of exciting for us to talk about
it. Yeah. I I even went back and like
parsed through it before we recorded,
and I still I think you're wrong. So
here we'll talk about it.
>> All right. We'll debate it.
[clears throat] So, it's called breaking
into thousands of cloud-based VPNs with
one bug. And this is a talk by David
Cash and Rich Warren. I'm sure these
guys are are legends um outside of the
bug bounty industry. I'm sure they're
like amazing hackers. Um I think that
they're from uh the UK, but anyways,
[snorts]
they basically found a bunch of bugs in
Zcaler and Net Scope. I think presumably
it seemed like it was because they they
run into them so often on their pin
tests and so they wanted to kind of
like, you know, be able to really
compromise them. Um I personally um
thought that one of the coolest things
they did and in their slide uh deck like
every few slides once they found
vulnerabilities they would like check it
off. They basically created a wish list
of bugs and in general I think that like
achievement or like um you know a task
based hacking is really valuable. We've
talked about a little bit on the pod. I
think you specifically do this kind of a
lot, right? When you're going to live
hacking event, it's like, oh, I want RC
on this feature or I want to be able to
like listen to anybody's conversation in
this device, right? It's like you set up
a goal and then you go and get it. And
usually somehow it's just like the stars
align to make it possible. It's probably
because everything is vulnerable if you
work hard enough.
>> Yeah.
>> Um [snorts]
but I think that's just really cool um
as like a takeaway for bug hunters is
like a wish list. Um I did think that it
was neat they had a multiple items on
their wish list, right? Like I feel like
as hackers sometimes we go to events
saying like, "Oh, an RC and this thing."
is just like one. Having the wish list
is pretty neat because you can probably
pivot between them.
>> Yeah. I I think there's, you know, a
point of diminishing returns with that
as well, right? Like you're like you
need to stay focused, but maybe, you
know, be open to the possibilities of
how the system is implemented, you know,
where the vulnerabilities might be.
>> Um, but I definitely like that concept
as well, and I think it's especially
applicable to appliances and IoT devices
or whatever, right? because um you know
[clears throat] oftentimes there are
just very specific things you want to do
like pontoon own all about shelling the
device right um and so you've got a very
narrow focus there and it makes it a lot
more intense for sure
>> yeah so I personally was surprised by
how much absc there was in this you may
you may disagree but I mean there was
like so many slides they had that
basically like here's the HTTP request
and here's the HTTP response and like
kind of were breaking it down which I
was delightfully pleased by um because
they were often looking at like um you
know the desktop installs of these apps.
Um, but anyways, they uh the one thing
that I thought was like a really great
takeaway was they found pre-author
configs for both Zscaler and Net Scope.
And I'm pretty sure that still existed
today. That wasn't like some
vulnerability. I think that what was in
there was a little bit too much data.
Whenever I was at App Omni and did SAS
security, I also found this on Workday.
For example, a lot of SASbased uh apps
that are like multi-tenant will for some
reason have like some sort of like
externally available config. It'll
usually include things like the org name
or some other stuff and you can um you
can like garner a little bit of
information about it. Sometimes it's not
it's usually not a vulnerability, but it
gives you a lot of information about the
target. In this case, a couple of them
were actually vulnerabilities, but I
thought that it was um I thought that it
was pretty neat. Um you can see uh
actually well I won't share but for the
audience there's a um there's an
endpoint for net scope that's like
getmobile userpack
um and then question mark org key and so
as long as you have the org key u which
is able to be found in a couple
different ways they talk about in the
talk so you should go watch that but you
can like return a bunch of information
about that org and it very often
included sensitive things like routes uh
internal host external host um and in
some cases it even include keys and
stuff. But um I thought that that was uh
one thing is neat. I I like meta
concepts and I think in SAS having like
a pre-auth config as like a meta concept
to know to look for or to like Google
force like if you're trying to target a
specific you know desktop thing or SAS
thing and you're like hey what's the
pre-auth config URL for this app right
and then that gives you more information
about it and sometimes might be leaking
things it shouldn't. Dude, those those
meta ideas are just going to become more
and more and more valuable though as you
know as well as we move into a bunch of
AI stuff supplemented hacking over the
next couple years because those meta
concepts are going to be able to be
pulled out and applied specifically. Um
yeah, [clears throat] totally. Uh and
and I think I've definitely seen this as
well, you know, with these appliances
you've got to look for. I mean, it's
this is kind of what it boiled down to.
You know, I I kind of covered this in a
talk a while back when I was talking
about my approach to hacking Graphana um
back in like 2020, but essentially it's
like you just got to look at the routes.
You know, look at the routes, look at
the unauthenticated routes, and then
that is your what you can work with, you
know, you got you if you want an
unauthenticated bug, you've got two
options. You bypass off or you work with
the unauthenticated routes, you know,
like [laughter]
>> and so uh you know, you just kind of
break it down into the steps and you
work through them. Um but yeah, I I
thought that that talk was really
interesting. I I think that there's
certainly a lot of um there's certainly
a lot of appsack in there like you were
saying right a lot of a lot of um you
know web hacking and uh I think a lot of
the IoT hacking that you actually do
with these apps is to get to the apps
stuff right is to get to the web hacking
right so I think that makes a lot of
sense to me um you just got to try to
keep pushing at the IoT you know side
until you get the source code or you're
able to like proxy the traffic and
understand what's actually happening in
these in the realm of like
communication. So
>> yeah, they they blast right by it in the
talk um and I don't have it in my notes
here, but one of the things they like
very quickly did was there was some sort
of like client side encryption or
something um that was like you know
signed by like an AES key and then that
like by figuring that out then you were
able to actually like see like what was
actually going on, what was in the
request and all that. I think that's
something that when I often run into
something, you know, complicated like
that client side, I usually just like
move on. But I think that figuring that
sort of stuff out is like obviously the
the birth of all bugs. Like that's like
that's where the real bugs are found.
>> Yeah. Big big breakthrough moments there
for sure. Like I remember in my very
limited experience of hacking routers
like this has happened twice and you
know where we needed to push some you
know public key by some endpoint and
then that opens up just like a ton of
different you know RPC calls or whatever
we can do uh over a different protocol
very
>> you mentioned like hardware a couple
times. This was all cloud-based VPN so I
think that it was all just software
related.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I'm I'm I'm talking more
about like appliances, right? you know,
I'm thinking about it from an IoT
perspective because that's where a lot
of my experience is. I haven't like done
a bunch of like appliance hacking, but
like
>> the the principles are somewhat cross um
you know, cross applicable. The nice
thing about appliances though is that
oftentimes you can just you know jump
right into the software realm whereas
like you know with [clears throat]
hardware okay first I've got to like you
know either pull the chip off get the
firmware or I've got to figure out how
to get a shell on it so that I can like
then get access to the software layer.
Right. So
>> Right.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Cool. Um, yeah. So, in general, I
think that that's neat. They, um, said,
actually, this is at the bottom of my
notes, but there's still Net Scope um,
installs out there without secure
enrollment enabled. And so, in those,
you can, uh, basically still either
bypass off or get access to some of
these like sensitive information. So,
people should look for that. Um, and
there are CVEs and I'm pretty sure
they're PC's and stuff from their talk.
Uh the other main thing I wanted to
mention and this is something that me
and um Monkey Kieran found when we were
hacking a few different um SAS
application companies when we were at
App omni was just like bad SAML
implementations are everywhere. It's so
hard to like deploy SAML properly u
because it's just complicated right and
and devs really struggle to do it and um
yeah they they cracked both Net Scope
and Zcaler SML um implementations and
there are like a there's like recurring
things that are possible that I've seen
in my research and in stuff like this
one is that very often it's making sure
that they're like is a valid signature
and not that the signature is like good
for you. So if you have a cross or like
if you can go create an instance of this
or a tenant of the org and and like
create your own like signed sample
request it often just works for all for
all tenants.
>> Um and then the other things you can do
is a lot of times they won't validate
some of the fields in there. So as long
as it's a good signature the the fields
inside of the SL request can be
anything. So you can you can test for
other users, you can test for other
orgs. Um there are lots of things to
test for when it comes to SAML. And I
think that that doesn't get tested much
either because it is kind of
complicated. But with AI these days,
like all the all the top models can
write Python scripts that'll like sign
stuff for you. It's like it's not a big
deal at all anymore. Um and I think the
best way to test it is actually just to
create your own org and then you can
just like proxy your own traffic in your
own tenant and then just change it to
other users values or other org values.
>> Yeah. Yeah. It is a little bit more
challenging when you don't have the
ability to do that, right? You're just
kind of blackbox testing the SL
implementation. But there are there some
really good articles out there still. I
I remember there's one from uh Uber a
while back where somebody like totally
poned the SL implementations of Uber. Um
definitely a ton of good bugs there. And
I know I've been meaning to get ahacker
one uh the guy that keeps doing a bunch
of like crazy SAML stuff on here so we
could talk about that. But we do have a
pretty solid episode on SAML. Uh like I
forget which one it is, but it's way
back.
>> Yeah. And and uh but like that episode
I've gone back and listened to myself
talk about SAML. [laughter] uh in that
episode yourself with it.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, I think that one I hit
pretty often.
>> Um
>> all right, man.
>> Let's see. Next one that I want to talk
about. Uh I'll just This one's nice and
quick. Um
>> the title is examining access control
vulnerabilities in GraphQL. Uh it's like
a field study, right? And he's talking
about finding a bunch of vulnerabilities
in a target with GraphQL. Um, and I just
wanted to shout this one out because I
think this is a good example of like
good uh GraphQL testing. Uh, and he he
does he breaks it down quite a bit. Um,
and one of the ones that I kind of
walked away with like, oh yeah, that's
something I didn't really think about
before is the difference between broken
object property level authorization and
broken object level authorization. So,
you know, you sometimes will see
scenarios, especially in GraphQL, where,
you know, oh, you are supposed to be
able to access this object, but you're
not supposed to be able to access the
subpropy of the object, right? And and
that is where a lot of the
vulnerabilities lie in GraphQL.
>> That's interesting. Yeah, you're right.
Cuz like very often I should be able to
like view like user Justin email, but
not user Justin anything else, right?
It's like password because password
because if I go to your profile or
whatever, it'll pull the user object of
yours. And so that'll be like it'll have
some of those properties, but I won't be
able to see all of them.
>> Exactly. Exactly. So, just a quick shout
out if anybody's interested in doing
some GraphQL stuff and wanted to brush
up. Um, that is a good place.
>> Were there any crazy bugs in there that
you remember that you
>> There were there were a lot of crazy
ones, dude. It was It was a dating app
that they were
>> Oh, nice.
[laughter] Not
>> What was this What was his tool of
choice for testing it? Did he mention
it?
>> Uh, you know, I didn't even pay
attention to that. I was just looking at
the I was just looking at the the data.
Um,
>> yeah, sure.
>> So,
>> yeah. All right. Um, next up for you.
>> Yeah, sure. I'll do I'll do a quick one
from lower down in my list. Um, I've got
at least two quick ones, but one was um
so Defcon 33 smart bus or yeah, smart
bus, smart hacking, free Wi-Fi to total
control. This guy is insane. Um, well,
there's maybe two of them. Uh, but it
was mostly just one guy. Basically, he
he like lives in China. I think
Shanghai. But anyways, he's on a bus and
he gets into a traffic jam and just like
a like just like a classic hacker. He's
like, "Ah, let's just see if I can take
over this bus." Before he arrived at his
destination, he literally had taken the
free Wi-Fi, gotten access to like an
admin panel, pivoted to another admin
panel. There was like two two of them
had the had the username password admin
admin, got full access to like all the
recordings and all the controls for
every bus in his city. Uh, so one, it's
just it's it's like just a cool talk,
right? Of course. No way.
>> Um, but the thing that I thought that
was just interesting about it was it
felt very much like um those old those
old Hussein writeups
>> that were like you just get in via some
way and it's like and then this happened
and then this happened and then this
happened. You know, it felt like easy
mode bug bounty targets where you get
pre you get post off and everything's
just so easy and lined up for you. like
and then admin admin worked and then I
just found this route where it dumped
everything and then that you know that
led to a domain over here where I could
log in with Adam and admin again.
>> Dude, it's so good man. It's so good. I
love those scenarios. I like my pulse is
high right now just thinking [laughter]
about it, you know.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh my gosh. Yeah, dude. I mean
definitely, you know, things that aren't
pentested. I always forget because I
spend so much time, you know, in the
buck bounty world, but like how much of
a palooa it is when you just like tack
something that isn't, you know,
intentionally being hardened. Oh my
gosh.
>> Exactly.
>> It's crazy, man. Um, all right. So, next
one that I had here was pass key. That
was it on that one, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Uh, next one I had here is called
pass key poned turning web off against
itself. And this was very timely because
I see pass keys everywhere. uh all of a
sudden and uh and I was like ah I should
kind of understand this a little bit
better. So watched this uh this talk and
it was a very good explanation. Um
essentially for those of you guys that
haven't um
you know looked into it very much at all
uh the situation is this. You're just
doing a public key private key sort of
thing here. So you give the server you
know your public key or whatever. um
they're going to go ahead and correlate
that public key to your account once
you've done the registration. And then
uh whenever you want to log in, they'll
give you a challenge. You prove that you
have the private key and then they just
let you into your account, right? Um and
>> do they sometimes feel too easy to you?
>> What do you mean?
>> Oh, the the keys. Yeah. Oh, totally
100%.
>> Like sometimes I'm like is this this
feels too easy?
>> Yeah. Like I feel like like 2FA is
supposed to feel like a little bit
difficult, but it just feels like it
feels almost too easy. Totally. It feels
like it just like works without adding
any difficulty.
>> Yeah.
>> But maybe it's just like you're just I
guess confirming that like you know that
is your device, right? Because basically
if your device is pawned then you do
lose it.
>> Yeah. And and well I mean I've got it
hooked into one password or whatever. Um
same. Yeah.
>> Yeah. And and it just you know it pops
up. I hit and then boom, you know it's
like and then I'm in. I'm like, "Oh,
>> it doesn't it doesn't feel like true to
FA, you know,
>> but if they've got my one password, I'm
[__] anyway, you know, like it's like,
you know, what are you going to do?"
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> Um, so it's like it's pretty bad. Uh, so
I think it's fine, but but I do think
that like there's a lot of, um,
>> ways that the attacker can utilize this,
of course.
>> Yeah.
>> And so, uh, first, you know, I wanted to
make sure you guys understand the
private key, public key thing, and how
that that works. It makes sense if you
think about it. Um, and then uh what the
the guy mentioned here is that there's
actually a lot of attack surface here
for for attackers. And mostly what he
spent the time talking about was a
malicious extension. You know, people
just yeeting extensions into their
browser all the time and how easy it is
for that um extension to insert a
content script shim uh the
navigator.credentials calls, right,
which is how you register and get your
your um
>> your uh pass keys. And then
>> so that's what I was going to ask you
was like how does this because there it
does feel a little bit like voodoo magic
because on my on my Mac for example the
pass key is accessible if I use my
fingerprint
>> and on and on your phone or whatever I
think usually it's by face ID or
whatever but there has to be some sort
of yeah I guess uh interface between the
you know one password or the desktop or
whatever that is handing over the the
public key into the HTTP like in into
the browser which is then going to pass
it via HTTP. It feels weird. It feels
like it's like going from like a
physical desktop into HTTP land. And
they're like, I'm curious what that
interface is like.
>> Yeah, that's handled by the browser. You
know, the browser itself is exposing um
navigator.credentials, which is the
interface for pass keys. And then, you
know, all of your various um you know,
whether it be your desktop uh one
password or like your phone's
fingerprint or whatever,
>> those are all sort of inter interacting
with the browser from there. um which is
is pretty solid. Um but I think it's
really interesting as well is like you
can definitely use this for atto um by
shimming those uh that navigator
credentials thing um if you can trigger
somebody's uh like off for that in the
pass key and they approve it then you
know that um authentication material
right that that comes from the uh you
know them doing that that um pass key uh
activation can then be used as
authentication material to log into that
user's account. And furthermore, if you
shim it uh on registration, then you can
just link your own malicious pass key to
the victim's account. And I know that
there's going to be a lot of scenarios
where we're looking for atto
methodologies and it's going to require
a password to change password, but it's
not going to require, you know, any any
additional os to add a pass key. So, um,
be on the lookout for that as a way to
get atto once you've established XSS.
This makes me really curious. What are
the protections in the browser to
prevent like website A from um you know
basically requesting a pass key for
website B? Because then you like
basically have the shim, right? Like
because it's like it's your website, not
the website they're logging into. Like
like I'm really curious how that like
what the segmentation is there. Like if
you have XSS, can you all of a sudden
shim it? If you have a post message
listener, can you sh it? Like what does
it take on the page to be able to shim
it? Definitely XSS. Um,
yeah, I'm trying to think about how it
would emulate a different website. Uh, I
imagine that handled at the browser
level, like once you call those those
navigation credentials things, it's
like, oh, you know, this call is coming
from
>> rhinerator.com or whatever. Um, but I
think there's also, you know, obviously
the crypto cryptographic aspect of it,
uh, like where the server is giving you
a challenge, right? And then you're
you're going to complete that. Um, so
yeah, interesting stuff there. And and I
also think that, um, one of just going
back to the XSS angle, uh, that I think
it would be really cool to see something
an exploitation framework for this, uh,
that that can be generalized and just
kind of included a a as an XSS script
where, okay, boom, I got XSS. Now I'm
going to include this script which shims
the, um, the calls to uh,
navigator.credentials credentials and
then uh you know registers my my key
maliciously or whatever. Um
>> yeah, because that that's what you want
for your video PC's once you get XSS is
some sort of easy way to prove that it's
critical, right? It's like
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Here's a video of me showing that
with users I can actually like steal
their uh like get full atto including
the pass key bypass.
>> Yeah. And I'm actually going to pull
this up really quick and see if I can
find the
um yeah, the credentials here. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I just wanted to make
sure I was I was explaining this
correctly. But yeah, the the challenge
is coming from Okay. Yeah. Cool. We're
good. I think we're good. [laughter] It
is complicated stuff, man. You know, I
don't I don't know if you've had the
same vibe, but like whenever um you
know, I do the episode for like the um
top 10 web hacking techniques or or do
like a Devcon recap or something. I just
have to ingest so much material very
quickly and then be able to regurgitate
it in a in a way that is like easy to
explain and easy for the viewer to
understand. It's tricky, dude. It's
freaking tricky, man. I
>> I mean, I think there's a lot of grace
there, but you are definitely a person
who is hard on yourself and expects
>> I want I want to make sure that people
know how it works, you know? It's it's
it's important because I think a lot of
the the neurons need to fire as a
hacker, right? You know, like even if
you don't fully understand something, if
you heard Justin talk about it that one
time, then you're like, "Oh, I kind of
understand how that works
>> and that doesn't really align with how I
understand it, so maybe I should look
into that a little more." You know, it's
important. It's important.
>> Yeah, it is.
>> Um All right. All right, what you got
next?
>> Um, this is
one of [clears throat] the ones that
yeah, I thought was pretty interesting.
I am not a mobile guy, so uh you might
actually think that this uh part that I
have highlighted is like much more
interesting. I will mention how I got
it, but basically uh this talk is called
bypassing intent destination checks
launch anywhere privilege escalation.
And I mean the person's obviously wildly
intelligent. Their their name is Kedon
Hi. Qi D- NH E. Um but I thought that
like uh so it was like there was like a
focus on basically time of check to time
of use vulnerabilities and how Android
intents are like resolved and used. Um
and yeah, while you're parsing that, if
you want to explain it to the user in a
minute, that's great. But the one of the
main things I thought was super cool was
at the very end he basically gave a
prompt for how to find the bug using AI
in like uh codebase and I thought man
what a cool thing to add to the end of
your talk. Um, and I just, yeah, I wish
more people would do that, right? Like,
if you're looking for this and you're
not, you know, an like, like an expert
in this exact type of vulnerability,
here's the prompt you can use to ask AI
say, "Hey, here's the code, like here's
the decompiled code or whatever. Here's
here's the um thing I'm looking for.
Does this exist in this place?" And it
was like not like um a specific
signature for a thing. It was like when
this function is called in this way with
this context and not doesn't have this
protection, then it's vulnerable. And so
of course like the you know top models
today will under will be able to like
kind of understand that and then look
for it in the code and then tell you if
that type of thing is in the code. And I
just thought that was like really neat
that he did that.
>> Dude, that's super beautiful. Yeah, I
love that. I I mean that's that's the
the new, you know, or maybe improved
version of like here's the PC at the
end, you know, the PC video, right? You
know, uh you know, giving giving you the
script and and showing you how to use
it, that sort of thing. Giving a prompt
to actually detect some of these code
patterns. Um, you know, I wish I could
add more to what you were saying about
this. Um, but as I'm looking forward to
it, I or looking through this little,
you know, summary that you have here. I
didn't get the chance to read this one,
but uh, it it it seems very interesting.
So, I'm going to read a couple of these
these
>> um, very cool points here. It seems like
what he's talking about is something
that I've kind of played around a little
bit with just in post messages, which is
in web. And it's essentially you know uh
trying to use time of uh time of check
time of use race conditions to trick you
know things going on. And we see this in
post message where you know let's say
for example we send a message and it
does a fetch request and then it you
know checks the origin right and but in
that meantime you can do a very quick
swap of the origin where the event
source came from. And instead of just
pointing to a window reference, it says,
"Oh, okay. That's coming from my my
place or whatever, you know, my buddy
over here." And and then and then so it
says, "Okay, I'm going to do all the
things." And then when it responds, you
know, event.source.post message, uh then
by that time, you've already swapped it
back to your cache HTML page and now you
can, you know, snag the response, right?
So that's me thinking about it from a
web world. Um I'm seeing some very some
very um interesting pieces of that here
where he's talking about okay
identifying and extending the time
windows between security check and
intent launches and then using large
malformed Android manifest to slow down
the resolution process and widen time of
check time of use windows. Dude, I am so
excited to listen to this talk. Um damn.
>> Anytime there's like a gadget that slows
something down to get a race condition
through, it feels like that's just like
peak hacking.
>> Ah, dude. Yeah, I love race conditions.
trace conditions are so cool. Um, but
yeah, uh, dang, Joseph, come on. Be be
more of a mobile guy so you can explain
this.
>> No, if I was if I was, maybe I'd be able
to explain this better. But yeah, um,
>> basically uh, this little thing I did
want to tell you this little summary is
just so good and clean. And I was I used
the ask button in um in YouTube and
basically said like hey you know just as
like a practical bug bounty hunter what
are the big takeaways like the actual
like practical advice or things to look
for when I'm like um testing similar
things and this is what it came out with
which is very clean.
>> Okay I'm going to read this one summary
at the top. The bad resolve
vulnerability highlights that even if an
event or I'm sorry, excuse me, an intent
is checked and deemed safe at one point,
its resolution might change by the time
it's actually launched, creating a
window for privilege escalation. Oh my
gosh, I know what I'm doing right after
this.
>> What? So, Bad Resolve is an old
vulnerability. His new one is called
Launch Anywhere, I think. But what ex
what exactly does it mean by resolution
here? What what is the resolution of an
intent? Dude, I wish I I wish I knew
like but but you know the the the way
that I'm the way that I'm thinking of it
is you know they're they're checking
>> I'm how do how do I explain the the
resolution? I mean I'm almost thinking
it like a promise you know in
JavaScript. I don't know if that's
getting too
but but you know like and then you know
you check where it's from you know what
it's supposed to be doing and then by
the time it's actually used it's
swapped. So I think that's really cool.
I'm going to go I'm going to go check
this out a little bit further after
this. Um but yeah. Okay. Um,
>> sorry. This is one of those times when
we really need Joel back. We need to
like bring in like guest appearance Joel
here. Please come explain this to us.
Joel,
>> Joel. Yeah, dude. Uh, but but I mean I
totally feel you though, Ben. Some of
some of these times, you know, you
listen to some of these talks and you're
like, I know that this is really cool
and I can express, you know, to the
people that this is cool, but I cannot
explain all of it. Um,
>> okay. So, uh, one of the ones that I,
uh, chose was invoking Gemini agents
with Google Calendar Invite, which is
like very similar to a lot of the
research that we've done and talked
about before. Um, but there was a couple
things here that were good takeaways.
Essentially, the TLDDR of it was
>> Who gave this talk?
>> Uh, let me see. It's in the notes. I'll
I'll let you pull it up while I'm
talking about it. But, um, essentially
the TLDDR of this was, you know, they'd
invite you to a Google calendar event
and they'd say, "Hey, what's on my
calendar?" And then the prompt injection
would just do a bunch of crazy stuff.
So, you know,
>> you've reported this exact thing.
>> Yeah. Yeah, we have. [laughter] And and
uh but you know, in this scenario, it
like controlled windows, uh you know,
turned up the boiler, you know, turned
up your heat in your house, all sorts of
stuff.
>> Um
>> and I I thought one that that was really
amazing. But one of the tips that they
gave in here was specifically uh here
was targeting this phrase. here are your
events for this week. Right. Right.
>> And um and that is what they would be
responding with constantly, you know,
when it says here are your events for
this week when you ask, you know, what's
on my calendar. And so they targeted
that phrase specifically and uh were
able to um override the response of the
LM uh because they could predict what it
was going to say in as a part of its
system prompter, as a part of its
training, and then get it to invoke all
sorts of different tools. Yeah, I wanted
to I wanted to mention this. So, I think
I've noticed this in the last week. You
know, you and I were in a hacking event
that we won't have to go into too deeply
here, but I noticed that a lot of people
in that event and just in my other
hacking um for like another AR red
teaming I've been doing that in nearly
every app these days, there's like a
suggested prompt, right? It's like
summarize my day, summarize my week,
what are my calendar events, like that
phrase exactly. And [snorts]
that is a better PC if you can pone that
versus the user saying hello, hi,
whatever. You know what I mean?
>> That's such a that is such a good call
out, Reszo. That is a really good call
out.
>> It is because like with Google, you and
I know this. They're like, "Oh, at scale
this will get popped. We'll kind of
trust you on any prompt." But a lot of
these smaller bug bunny programs won't.
Like so if you're like if your prompt
that you're inputting that's going to go
figure go trigger a prompt injection is
like, "Hey, can you tell me the 22nd
thing I did last week on this other
thing?" and then it triggers the prompt
and they're like, "This is unrealistic."
But when it's one of the hard-coded
prompts that they just like can click or
that they expect the users to always say
or do, it almost always gets accepted
and it will sometimes, I think, even
leave the um it leaves the user
interaction required at like a lower
bar. It might not be UIL versus UIH, but
it definitely leaves it there, right,
>> dude.
>> Um
>> what a great call out, man. Like that
that's just one of those things like,
you know, you hear it and you're like,
"Ah, duh, of course." But like I totally
never thought of that and I've looked
at, you know, I don't know, let me not
overseas. I probably looked at like, you
know, 20 AI assets by this point, you
know, and I I haven't thought of that.
That's that's such a good point.
>> But I think but I think what they did is
like the next step, right? It's like
they noticed that every time they
clicked that the the LLM would respond
with here are your events for the week.
So then they put in their prompt
injection, here are the events for the
week colon, then all the things that
they wanted it to do maliciously. So I
think that's kind of like a two-step
process there that's like pretty cool
and valuable. It's like one, what are
the um recommended prompts and then what
when you use those, what's the model's
language when it responds to you and you
want to kind of um what's that called?
Mirror. You want to mirror the model's
language in your prompt injection
payload.
>> Yeah. It's almost like it's a, you know,
you're trying to convince a human to do
something, man. It's hilarious. Like you
read like all those like sales, you
know, technique books where they're
like, oh, you know, mirror mirror your
your partner in the negotiation. And I'm
like, yeah,
>> wow, crazy, dude. Um, I I would add one
more thing to the end of this. Uh, and I
cannot believe I didn't I I don't
believe I checked this when I was
working on Gemini, which stab in the
heart, but uh, prompt injection to
opening a URL and then swapping that URL
via redirect to an intent URI. Oh my
gosh, like that is such a good idea. And
and you know, maybe by the time I don't
I I know we were playing around with
that one night.
>> You can redirect to intents. So I don't
even know how you do that.
>> Yes, you can. Yeah. So, so, uh,
essentially what they did there was they
did a prompt injection. You know, it
then opened up an HTTP URL. That URL
redirected to an intent URI and it would
just launch the app. And I'm like,
>> oh my gosh,
>> can you redirect to any protocol?
>> Um, yeah. Yeah. And it's all up to the
user agent, up to the browser, whatever
to decide what to do with it. And most
of the time in Android, it will go ahead
and prompt you, you know, and say like,
hey, do you want to open the YouTube
app? Right. But in Gem, uh, this Gemini,
you know, thing that they were talking
about here, if you redirected to an
intent URI from within the like embedded
browser on in Gemini, it would just open
up the intent. And I'm like, oh my gosh,
that is such a crazy thing. And it made
me think of a pontoon own write up I
just recently um uh was was or it was a
video that I was watching um by Ken I I
can't remember his last name, Ken Ganon.
Um and essentially he was talking about
how you need delivery. Uh delivery is a
huge problem for um these devices that
you uh are trying to pone and pone to
own these mobile apps, right? How do I
without without user interaction, you
know, um trigger these these these uh
attacks and um
>> one of one of the ways that could
potentially do that is using these AI
apps, right? That normal usage, hey,
what's on my calendar, right? But that
that calendar has been has been
hijacked,
>> compromised.
>> Yep. And then it, you know, opens up an
HTTP URL which redirects to an intent
URI which triggers a vulnerability in
another mobile app that's, you know,
embedded on the device by default and
that triggers RC, right? I just think
that's that's like a that's a really
good chain and could be something good
for any of you guys that are looking at
trying to attack like like vanilla
mobile devices, thinking about AI and
then using those AIs to launch intents.
Do [snorts] you know if Google apps are
like more trusted in the Android
ecosystem? Like they're less likely to
require
um like approval.
>> Uh oh, you mean like, you know, do you
want to launch the YouTube app? That
sort of thing.
>> Yeah. It's like it's like if you're on
Android, it might automatically happen.
>> Okay. Well, what where this takes my
brain, which I think is going to be
huge, it makes me want to go test it
before this thing goes out.
>> I you know how I'm always thinking about
delivery for AI vulnerabilities. And one
thing is Q parameters, right? Where
>> um you know if you can you can basically
have a one click or a CSRF do a lot of
delivery on these apps where the query
is in like a a specific get parameter
and and then I remembered that um in
testing some of the desktop AI apps from
Frontier Labs, there is a specific
protocol like app name colon slash and
when you do that it automatically
invokes the prompt.
>> Yep. And so that makes me think that
these custom handlers especially on on
like mobile devices like if you open up
like a you know q parameter based link
via intent across claude across jbt
across gemini will it autoexecute those
prompts because if so then you have
automatic delivery.
>> Yeah dude. Yeah it's good. It's good
man. It's
>> I want to go test it. It's a good thing
to be thinking of. Um
>> yeah. Okay. Um, dude, I got to bounce
here in like two minutes, so let me uh
hit this last one and then if you want
to do another one, you can. And if not,
we'll cut it. Um, but uh, last one. This
one's kind of crazy. I'm not going to
lie, man. Like, this one blew my mind a
little bit. And I think I think it was
you that mentioned to me that Brandon
went to a talk on Dom Clumbering uh, at
these young guys. They're like, "Oh,
we're looking for internships." And it's
like, "You guys are super experts
already. Tell me more."
>> Yeah, dude. It was like I I mean the
these these were um you know university
they were associated with a university
or whatever. Um holy moly dude like
>> can we hire them? Have you reached out
to them yet?
>> They took I don't know man. We I got to
I got to talk to them or something. But
they they found a bunch of bugs uh
relating to dog plumbering in things
like Webpack's uh like bundler or
runtime code, right? So every website
uses Webpack ever, you know, and the
runtime code that comes along with that
was vulnerable to like a a DOM
clobbering and it's just like holy moly
like um but anyway essentially they took
domlobbering super far because there are
a lot of people that have kind of poked
at domlobbering and try to figure out
how to do it but essentially they
formalized the whole thing and they like
uh you know figured out okay we know
exactly what things we can overwrite
with dump clobbering um then we're going
to like hook those and do a taint
analysis and then build like the a tree
and correlate those to like the
structure of the HTML that we would need
to like mimic that flow uh to get you
know our source to hit the sync and they
just like formalized the whole thing and
like uh made it so essentially you know
it would trace the code you know via
taint analysis and then it it would say
um okay according to this tree this is
the DOM clobbering payload we need to
reach the sync and then it would
generate that payload automatically and
then detect tech whether it hit the sync
and they like they cleaned up with it
like almost 500 zero days um
and bugs on Webpack, RSpack, uh Vite I
think is how it's pronounced. I've never
had to say that out loud before. Um
Google API client library.
>> How many How many How many of these do
you think are being exploited by bug
hunters in the wild? 500 zero days.
>> Yeah, dude. Well, it does require an
HTML injection though, which is
interesting, right? Um,
and so, you know, you've got to find
that base piece, but once you've got it,
then you've got these gadgets, right?
And that
>> not anymore. Not if all these got fixed.
>> Well, yeah, a lot of them did get fixed,
but a lot of them are not fixed still.
So, um, you can check out the GitHub uh
link. It's Dom Clbering Collection by
Jack from East. Um, and, uh, we'll link
it in the description, but the tool that
they built is called the Hulk that does
this automatically. Um, holy moly, dude.
It was crazy.
>> All right, let me do my two super quick.
It will take me literally one one minute
each.
>> Go for it, man.
>> Uh, because these were not long. First
of all, there was one by Mate Jose or
yeah, Mati. Um, it's called smart
devices, dumb resets, testing firmware
persist persistence and commercial IoT
devices. Dude, this is one of those ones
that I was like, we should have covered
this on the spooky episode. Basically,
really cool. Well, Matt Brown got a
shout shout out in it, but um basically
he would buy devices like routers, flash
the firmware with OpenWRT, return them,
and then see if they if they did
anything or if they just shipped them to
a new customer totally backed and they
would just ship them out. He somehow set
up some like thing where he could pull
from to make sure he bought it. And his
PC was something that would literally
just make a get request to his server so
it wasn't malicious. But he he found out
that there's basically zero validation
on the market of returns. So, if you're
ever going to buy an IoT device or a
router or something, the the like it
just scared me about that because now I
just don't know whether the firmware is
going to be back doorored.
>> Yeah, dude. That's crazy
>> crazy talk. So, you should look that up
if you're interested in that. The other
thing was there was one called Mac PRT
cookie theft and intra ID persistence
and um yeah, I it was one of those that
was like way over my head. basically a
bunch of like low-level like Mac OS
hacking and stuff. And um anyways, the
thing I wanted to bring up was they talk
a lot about SSO and I think that if
there are any of our listeners who are
like just so experts or want to
understand so better, I think you should
definitely check that out because um it
got into they had a bunch of really neat
diagrams and a bunch of really neat
explanations for how different forms of
work and how they're implemented from
like a desktop perspective and then a
lot of it was clearly applicable to
ABSAC too. So that's it.
>> All right, man. Very good. I I I do want
to say on that last note uh that is also
an IoT attack vector by the way is if
you're you can persist a factory reset
on the device that is a valid bug in my
opinion uh and with some of the IoT
people that I've I've dealt with. So
it's just not like a threat vector thing
I think of very often. But yeah.
>> All right, man. Is that a wrap?
>> Yep. That's a wrap. Thanks.
>> Peace y'all. And that's a wrap on this
episode of Critical Thinking. Thanks so
much for watching to the end, y'all. If
you want more critical thinking content,
uh, or [music] if you want to support
the show, head over to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening [music] there on
top of master classes, hackalongs,
exclusive content, and a full-time
hunters guild. If you're a full-time
hunter, it's a great time. Trust me. All
right, I'll see you there.